hey gang and welcome to your very first docker tutorial
嘿，帮派，欢迎来到你的第一个docker 教程
[Music] so then i've been meaning to make a
[音乐]所以我一直想做一个
docker tutorial for a while now but it always got sidelined because there was
docker 教程有一段时间了，但它总是被搁置，因为
another series that i wanted to make first but now i've decided to bring it
我想先制作另一个系列，但现在我已经 决定给
the attention it deserves and create a crash course all about it
它应有的关注并创建一个关于它的速成课程，
so docker is one of those things that sometimes gets overlooked by new
所以 docker 是新开发人员有时会忽略的东西之一，
developers because at first glance it's hard to understand why we might use it
因为乍一看很难理解为什么我们会使用它，
but it's definitely worth investing your time into because it can make developing
但绝对值得花时间 因为它
applications either on your own or in a team much easier to manage and the way
可以使您自己或团队开发应用程序更容易管理，
it does that is by using what's known as containers to run applications in
它的方式是使用所谓的容器
isolated environments on a computer like a node application for example or a
在计算机上的隔离环境中运行应用程序，例如节点应用程序或
react application or a mongodb service or something else entirely like a python
反应 应用程序或 mongodb 服务或其他完全类似于 python
application now we'll be talking more about containers later in the course but
应用程序的东西现在我们将在课程后面更多地讨论容器，
the crux of it is this imagine if i was in a dev team and i was
但关键是这个想象我 f 我在一个开发团队中，我
making an application in a node.js environment and that node.js version
正在 node.js 环境中制作应用程序，
that i needed for the application was a very specific version that had a feature
而我需要的应用程序的 node.js 版本是一个非常特定的版本，它具有
i needed to use now also imagine that i wanted to share the application with
我现在需要使用的功能也想象我想要 与
another person on my team so that they can run it on their computer as well
我团队中的另一个人共享应用程序，以便他们也可以在他们的计算机上运行它，
well before they do that they'd have to set up their development environment to
然后他们必须设置他们的开发环境以
match mine to make sure the application runs correctly for example they'd have
匹配我的，以确保应用程序正确运行，例如他们会 必须
to have the same version of node.js installed that the application needs to
安装应用程序需要
run correctly they'd also need to install all the project dependencies and
正确运行的相同版本的 node.js 他们还需要安装所有项目依赖项并
set up any configuration like environment variables to make sure
设置任何配置（如环境变量）以确保
everything works the same way so there'd be a significant setup
一切以相同的方式工作，所以会有 一个重要的设置
process just to get the application running on
过程只是为了让应用程序在
another computer now imagine the same scenario but with
另一台计算机上运行现在想象相同的场景，但有
multiple other applications as well all requiring their very own specific
多个其他应用程序以及都需要它们自己的特定
environment setup and these applications might need to be run on multiple
环境设置 并且这些应用程序可能需要在多台
different machines well that would mean a lot of setup
不同的机器上运行，这意味着
every time we want to run a different application which requires a different
每次我们想要运行不同的应用程序时都需要进行大量设置，
development environment even on our own machines because different applications
即使在我们自己的机器上也需要不同的开发环境，因为不同的应用程序
might require different versions of node or python or php or something else and
可能需要不同版本的节点或 python 或 php 或其他东西，
that's where docker and containers come into play
这就是 docker 和容器发挥作用的地方，
so you can think of a container for now as like a box or a package that contains
因此您现在可以将容器视为一个盒子或一个包，其中包含
everything our application needs to run so all the source code dependencies the
我们的应用程序运行所需的所有内容，因此所有源代码都依赖于
correct runtime environment and versions etc and this container can run our
正确的运行时环境和 版本等，这个容器可以运行我们的
application then in isolation away from any other processes on our computer so
应用程序，然后与我们计算机上的任何其他进程隔离，因此在我们的计算机
it wouldn't matter what versions of node or python or anything else is installed
上安装什么版本的 node 或 python 或其他任何东西都没有关系，
on our computer because everything the application needs to run is inside the
因为应用程序需要运行的所有内容都在里面
container and then this makes it much easier for me or other people in my team
容器，然后这使我或我团队中的其他人更
to run these different applications on our computers and we wouldn't need to
容易运行这些不同的我们的计算机上的应用程序，我们不需要
worry about setting up different versions of anything or installing
担心设置任何东西的不同版本或安装
dependencies because it's all in the container itself a predictable
依赖项，因为它们都在容器本身中 一个可预测的
consistent and isolated environment the only thing that i or someone else
一致和隔离的环境我或
running these containers will need on their computer is docker to manage those
运行这些容器的其他人唯一需要的东西 计算机是 docker 来管理这些
containers and that's at the heart of what docker
容器，这是 docker 的核心，
is all about it's a tool for managing containers
它是一个管理容器的工具，
so again this is a simplified overview of what docker and containers are all
所以这再次是对 docker 和容器的简化概述
about and we'll look at more detail into how they work later on and also how they
，我们将更详细地了解它们是如何实现的 稍后工作，以及他们
can improve the deployment of applications to a server as well because
如何改进应用程序到服务器的部署，
much in the same way that containers can be run on your own or somebody else's
因为与容器可以在您自己或其他人的计算机上运行的方式相同，
computer they can also be pulled onto your production
它们也可以被拉到您的生产
server and that way you don't need to configure the server because all the
服务器上，这样您就不用 不需要配置服务器，因为所有
configuration and setup is in the container already now you might be
配置和设置都已经在
thinking well what about virtual machines can't they solve the same
容器中 t 虚拟机不能解决
problem that containers solve and yeah they can but there's some differences
容器解决的相同问题，是的，它们可以解决问题，但是有些
which sometimes make containers a better option first of all each virtual machine
差异有时会使容器成为更好的选择，首先
that you make runs its own fully blown operating system with its own kernel and
，您制作的每个虚拟机都运行自己的完整操作系统和自己的内核，并且
that's running on top of your host computer's operating system whatever
它运行在您的主机操作系统之上，无论
that might be but containers don't they share the host
可能是什么，但容器不共享
computer's operating systems kernel and so they're more lightweight than virtual
主机的操作系统内核，因此它们比虚拟机更轻量级
machines and less bloated it also means that they're typically quicker to start
并且不那么臃肿，这也意味着它们通常更快
up and they use less memory on your computer
启动并且它们在您的计算机上使用更少的内存
now containers do include a slimmed down version of a specific operating system
现在容器确实包含特定操作系统的精简版本，
but they still use the host machine's kernel under the hood
但它们仍然在引擎盖下使用主机的内核，
so essentially containers are much more lightweight and quicker than virtual
因此基本上容器比虚拟机更轻量级和更快，
machines although both can solve the same problems and there will be times
尽管两者都可以解决同样的问题，
when you'd prefer a virtual machine to a container so it's not a case of one is
有时你更喜欢虚拟机而不是容器，所以它不是一个 一个
better than the other for everything but anyway now we have this kind of
比另一个好，但无论如何，现在我们对
bird's eye view of what docker and containers are all about the next step
docker 和容器的全部内容有了这种鸟瞰图，下一步
is to install docker and start using it we'll be doing that in the next lesson
是安装 docker 并开始使用它，我们将在下一课中这样做
but first of all i just want to finish up this one with a few side points
但首先我只是想用几个方面来结束这个，
so first of all before you start this course you should probably have a little
所以首先在你开始这门课程之前，你可能应该有
bit of experience in web development in general maybe you've created node
一点 web 开发的经验，也许你已经创建了节点
applications react sites or something like that nothing specific but you've
应用程序反应站点或 类似的东西没有什么特别的，但是您
got a general understanding of web dev in this series my code examples are
对本系列中的 Web 开发
mainly going to consist of node and javascript so it might be slightly
有了大致的
beneficial if you know a little bit about those first of all
so how to make for example a simple node express app or how to use nodebomb but
了解 例如，制作一个简单的 nodeexpress 应用程序或如何使用 nodebomb，
it's not absolutely essential i'm also going to be using docker with react
但这并不是绝对必要的，我还将
later in the series but again you don't really need to know much about react to
在本系列的后面使用docker 做出反应来
learn the docker side of things but i'm not going to pretend that it won't be
学习 docker 方面的东西，但我不会
useful to know the basics now if you want to learn some of that first i've
假装现在知道基础知识没有用，如果你想先学习一些基础知识，我
got loads of tutorials available all about node javascript react and much
有很多关于 node javascript 的教程
more both on youtube at the net ninja pro site so i'm going to leave some of
在 youtube 上的 net ninjapro 网站上做出反应等等，所以我将在视频下方留下一些
those links to those other courses down below the video
指向其他课程的链接
i've also created course files for different lessons in this tutorial
我还为本教程系列中的不同课程创建了课程文件，
series you can find them all at this repo docker crash course and i'll leave
你可以找到它们 全部在这个repo docker 速成课程中，我
the link down below the video so if you want to see the code for a specific
将把链接留在视频下方，所以如果你想查看特定
lesson for example lesson five you'd select the lesson five branch right here
课程的代码，例如第五课，你可以在这里选择第五课分支
and then you'd see all of the code inside that branch now if you want to
，然后你会看到现在该分支中的所有代码如果您想
download a specific lesson you select the lesson then go to this code button
下载特定课程，请选择课程然后转到此代码按钮
and select download zip and that's going to download a zip folder of that
并选择下载 zip，这将为您下载该特定课程的 zip 文件夹，
particular lesson for you so again this link to this repo is going to be down
因此再次链接到此 回购将下跌 n
below the video so anyway that's your introduction to docker in the next
在视频下方，所以无论如何这是您在下一课中对 docker 的介绍，
lesson we're going to go ahead and install docker on our computer
by the way if you want to watch this entire course now without youtube
如果您现在想在没有 youtube 广告的情况下观看整个课程，我们将继续在我们
adverts you can do it's all up on the net ninja website netninja.dev you can
的计算机上安装 dockernet ninja 网站 netninja.dev 您可以花
buy the course for two dollars to get instant access to all of it or you can
2 美元购买课程以立即访问所有课程，或者您可以
sign up to net ninja pro and get instant access to all of my courses without
注册 net ninja pro 并立即访问我的所有课程而无需
adverts as well as premium courses not found on youtube including my udemy ones
广告以及未找到的高级课程 在 youtube 上，包括我的 udemy 的
that's nine dollars a month and you can get your first month half price when you
，每月 9 美元，当您在这里使用此促销代码时，您可以获得第一个月的半价
use this promo code right here so i'm gonna leave this link down below in the
，所以我将在视频说明下方留下这个链接
video description for you to sign up and i really hope you enjoyed this series
供您注册，我真的 希望你喜欢这个系列
and please do not forget to share subscribe and like the videos that
，请不要忘记分享订阅和
really helps a lot and i'm going to see you in the very next lesson
喜欢真正有帮助的视频，我将在下一课见到你